UMA MAHARJAN

API AUTOMATION TESTER

CONTACT

umamaharjan2022@outlook.com

(469)996-4438

SKILLS

languages JAVA, C#.Net, SQL, Selenium Automation tool IDE Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, Visual Studio

Databases SQL, Excel

Test Framework JUnit, NUnit, Selenium WebDriver

Operating System Windows, Linux, Mac

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Science

Grand Canyon University, Phoenix, Arizona 2018-2022

ABOUT

Looking opportunity in QA/QE role with over 10+ years of extensive experience in Testing Application along with Manual and automated testing. Improved the automated testing by extending the coverage to 90% on existing software application. Implemented sanity testing on added feature through automation on every release and over the time completed full feature testing. My expertise with underlying test plan to carried out testing of the product with both Manual and Automation propelled high-standard QA deliverables. Additionally, I have been successful in developing test scenarios/plans, integrating/debugging automated tests, and tracking/monitoring results & defects

WORK EXPERIENCE

API Automation Tester

GameStop Inc., Grapevine, Texas | 03/2018 – current

Manual and Automation Testing of API of Game console text fixture

- Create automation Suites to validate functionality, reliability, performance, and security testing of the Application Programing Interface (API).
- Write a separate test plan for Manual and Automate tests for the API and execute them.
- Configure developer environment tools and checks, debug and troubleshoot failure and analyze root cause of the issue
- Improve project transparency and collaboration with stakeholders and write a proper documentation of each setup required for each setup automation.
- Improve overall test accuracy and efficiency by participating in code reviews, ensuring coding standards.
- Triage issue found by Customer or QE and update automation to cover the scenario.

Software Developer

GameStop Inc., Grapevine, Texas | 03/2013 – 03/2018

Software application developer for one of the Game console fixture

- Created an application using C# application and SQL database to enter the information of the game console when entered in the facility till shipment.
- Analyzed and resolved the root cause of the issue and improved the existing application.
- Communicate with the Software architect for designing and updating software database.
- Resolved complex technical design issues.
- Created a unit testing of the design application before hand over to QE.
- Delivered high quality application on time even when working on multiple application.
- Spearheaded the integration and debugging of automated tests and tracked the resolution of identified defects.
- Effectively monitored results of unit tests and maintained databases of results for further analysis.

QA Tester

GameStop Inc., Grapevine, Texas | 08/2011 – 03/2013

Software Application Test of Game Console

- Tested video games and work closely with the development team.
- Created a test plan for QA team to validate the console fixture by the technician.
- Inspect random game console verified by the QA Team to confirm the Quality of product.
- Created different environments for validating game console.
- Review the issue found on game console from customer and updated existing test plan.
- Validated dispatched game console is entered in the database correctly.
- Pull up stored data of all fixed game console before dispatch and verify information such as when game console was entered to the system, issue of the console, technician who resolve the issue, amount of service to resolve were added correctly and all the necessary field were added correctly.
- Sign off and release the game console dispatch for the shipment

Software Application Manual Tester

ATC Logistic Inc., Fort Worth, Texas | 04/2007 – 07/2011

QE Tester of logistic Software Application

- Create/update the test plan for new features/ added features based on provided specification of the product.
- Validate the Test plan of each test cases with the Team before executing it.
- Thorough testing on the new features and responsible on running regression test to ensure added features won't affect the existing features on the application/product.
- Validate data of each data stored in SQL Server of each input data from the application.
- Uses erroneous parameter values to validate graceful recovery of incorrect feature use.
- Validated dispatched game console is entered in the database correctly.
- Take an extensive measure to validate using negative test cases to verify the product/software.